Guide to the Gary P. and Sandra G. Baden Collection of Print Advertisements, 1840-1986 and undated RL.11193
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Gary P. and Sandra G. Baden Collection of Print Advertisements
1840-1986 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Baden, Gary
Baden, Sandra
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11193
32.0 Linear Feet
Arrangement
Arranged into the following series: Automotive; Business; Fashion; Food and Beverage; Health and Beauty; Household and Other; Tobacco; Tourism and Travel; Non-Advertising Materials; and Newsprint.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Gary P. and Sandra G. Baden Collection of Print Advertisements were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1998-2004.
Related Materials
Realted materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections: J. Walter Thompson Company Domestic Advertisements; J. Walter Thompson Company Competitive Advertisements; J. Walter Thompson Company International Advertisements; Roy Lightner Collection of Antique Advertisements
Collection Overview
Collection spans 1840-1986 and includes newspaper and magazine clippings and tear sheets, catalogs, ephemera, memorabilia, and other printed material primarily from the U.S., Great Britain, and France. Advertisements represent products and services from a wide range of categories including alcoholic and non-alcoholic beverages, businesses, cosmetics and other health and beauty products, fashion (including clothing, jewelry and watches), food, hotels and other tourist and travel destinations, household products, movies and theater events, tobacco products (primarily cigarettes) and transportation (airlines, automobiles, buses, cruise lines, trains, tires and other automotive accessories). The bulk of materials are in English, but French, Greek, and Spanish-language items are also present. Companies represented include Ford, Packard, Chrysler, Chevrolet, Coca Cola, TWA, Henri Bendel, Goodyear, and DeBeers. Non-advertising related materials include sheet music from the vaudeville, ragtime, and minstrel era; World War I; and depictions of African Americans, Native American, and other ethnicities in advertisements and print media. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising -- Automobiles; Fashion -- United States -- History; Advertising -- Food; Advertising -- Alcoholic beverages -- United States; Advertising -- Cosmetics; Advertising -- Tobacco -- United States -- History; Advertising -- Hotels -- United States; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
- Automotive, 1897-1974; 1
  - Cars, 1899-1974; 1
    - Abbott-Detroit, 1911-1912 (Box 1)
    - Auburn/Cord, 1928-1937 (Box 1)
    - Austin (UK), 1918-1950 (Box 1)
    - Autocar, 1903-1920 (Box 1)
    - Baker Electric, 1906-1913 (Box 1)
    - Ballot (France), 1923 (Box 1)
    - Brewster, 1907-1908 (Box 1)
    - Briscoe, 1915-1919 (Box 1)
    - Buick, 1918-1953 (Box 1)
    - Cadillac, 1904-1961 (Box 1)
    - Chalmers, 1912-1921 (Box 1)
    - Chandler, 1916-1920 (Box 1)
    - Chevrolet, 1923-1957 (Box 1)
    - Chrysler, 1925-1959 (Box 1)
    - Cole, 1919 (Box 1)
    - Columbia/Columbia Electric, 1904-1920 (Box 1)
    - Columbus, 1910 (Box 1)
    - Corbin, 1907 (Box 1)
    - Daimler/Mercedes, 1904-1958 (Box 1)
    - De Soto, 1928-1954 (Box 1)
    - Dodge, 1915-1954 (Box 1)
    - Duesenberg, 1918-1934 (Box 1)
    - Elmore, 1905-1911 (Box 1)
    - Fiat, 1905-1906 (Box 1)
    - Fisher, 1922-1931 (Box 1)
    - Ford, 1905-1954 (Box 1)
    - Franklin, 1905-1928 (Box 1)
    - Garford, 1913 (Box 1)
    - Georges Irat (France), 1922-1923 (Box 1)
    - Graham-Paige, 1928-1929 (Box 1)
    - Haynes-Apperson, 1902-1920 (Box 1)
    - Hillman (UK), 1949 (Box 1)
    - Holsman, 1907-1908 (Box 1)
    - Hudson/Essex, 1920-1950 (Box 1)
    - Humber (UK), 1919-1931 (Box 1)
    - Hupp/Yeats/Hupmobile, 1911-1935 (Box 1)
    - Inter-State, 1912 (Box 1)
    - Jaguar, 1958 (Box 1)
    - Jeep/Willys/Overland, 1910-1949 (Box 1)
    - Jordan, 1920-1923 (Box 1)
    - Kaiser-Frazer, 1946-1949 (Box 1)
    - Kissel Kar, 1917-1918 (Box 1)
    - Knox, 1905-1908 (Box 1)
    - LaFayette, 1920-1923 (Box 1)
    - Lincoln, 1924-1956 (Box 1)
    - Locomobile, 1901-1920 (Box 1)
    - Marmon, 1906-1931 (Box 1)
    - Maxwell, 1908-1923 (Box 1)
    - Mercury, 1939-1957 (Box 1)
    - Metz, 1910-1915 (Box 1)
    - Milburn, 1917 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous, 1905-1932 (Box 2)
    - Mitchell, 1904-1917 (Box 2)
    - Mobile, 1900-1901 (Box 2)
    - Moon, 1920 (Box 2)
    - Morris (UK), 1921-1959 (Box 2)
    - Nash/Rambler, 1928-1954 (Box 2)
    - National, 1914-1920 (Box 2)
    - Newsprint, 1915-1926 (Box 2)
    - Northern, 1905-1907 (Box 2)
    - Oakland, 1920-1921 (Box 2)
    - Oldsmobile, 1904-1950 (Box 2)
    - Packard, 1904-1950 (Box 2)
    - Paige, 1918-1923 (Box 2)
    - Peerless, 1904-1928 (Box 2)
    - Pierce-Arrow, 1903-1931 (Box 2)
    - Plymouth, 1928-1949 (Box 2)
    - Pontiac, 1920-1959 (Box 2)
    - Pope, 1903-1911 (Box 2)
    - Rambler, 1903-1910 (Box 2)
    - Rauch Lang Electric, 1911-1915 (Box 2)
    - Regal, 1910 (Box 2)
    - REO/Premier/Owen, 1905-1936 (Box 2)
    - Rolls-Royce, 1925-1931 (Box 2)
    - Saxon, 1916 (Box 2)
    - Scripps-Booth, 1917-1919 (Box 2)
    - Searchmont, 1903 (Box 2)
    - Speedwell, 1911-1912 (Box 2)
    - Standard, 1920-1921 (Box 2)
    - Stearns, 1906-1907 (Box 2)
    - Stevens-Duryea, 1911 (Box 2)
    - Studebaker, 1899-1956 (Box 2)
    - Stutz, 1918-1931 (Box 2)
    - Sunbeam/Talbot (UK), 1919-1953 (Box 2)
    - Templar, 1920 (Box 2)
    - Thomas, 1911-1912 (Box 2)
    - Thompson, 1919 (Box 2)
    - Triumph (UK), 1957-1959 (Box 2)
    - Warren-Detroit, 1910 (Box 2)
    - Wayne, 1905-1912 (Box 2)
    - Whippet, 1928-1929 (Box 2)
    - White, 1905-1915 (Box 2)
    - Winton, 1904-1920 (Box 2)
    - American Motors/Rambler, Auburn,Austin/MGB, Anderson, Allen, 1910-1969 (Box 14)
    - Bentley, Carhart, Case, Century, Chandler, Chalmers, Citroen, Cole, Cord, Datsun, Decanville, Detroit, DeVaux, Duesenberg, DuPont, Durant, 1905-1969 (Box 14)
    - Buick, 1916-1967 (Box 14)
    - Cadillac/Lasalle, 1912-1965 (Box 14)
    - Cheverolet, 1928-1967 (Box 14)
    - Chrysler, 1926-1965 (Box 14)
    - Daimler Mercedes, 1911-1965 (Box 15)
    - DeSoto, 1931-1961 (Box 15)
    - Dodge, 1915-1965 (Box 15)
    - EMF, Essex, Everitt, Hupmobile, Interstate, Imperial, Jackson, Jordan, King, Lewis, 1910-1961 (Box 15)
    - Ford, includes Edsel, English Ford (Cortina, etc), 1925-1966 (Box 15)
    - Franklin, 1906-1931 (Box 15)
    - Gardner, Garford, Graham, Harley-Davidson, Hudson, Jaguar, Jordan, 1912-1957 (Box 15)
    - General Motors, 1931-1965 (Box 15)
    - Jeep/Willys/Overland, 1910-1965 (Box 15)
    - Kaiser/Frazer/Henry J, 1946-1952 (Box 15)
    - Lafayette, Lion, Locomobile, Marathon, Marmon, Maxwell, Michigan, Midland, Mitchell, Milburn, Moon, Ohio Electric, 1909-1929 (Box 15)
    - Lincoln, 1922-1959 (Box 15)
    - Mercury, 1946-1966 (Box 16)
    - Nash, 1926-1956 (Box 16)
    - Oakland, Paige Jewett, Parry, Peerless, Pierce-Arrow, 1905-1935 (Box 16)
    - Oldsmobile, 1903-1965 (Box 16)
    - Packard includes Studebaker, 1914-1967 (Box 16)
    - Plymouth, 1937-1965 (Box 16)
    - Pontiac, 1928-1966 (Box 16)
    - Pope, Pan-America, Queen, Rambler, RCH, Regal, Reo, Roamer, Rubay, Saab, Sunbeam, 1905-1966 (Box 17)
    - Schacht, Speedwell, Standard, Stearns-Knight, Stephens, Stevens-Duryea, Stutz, Sultan, Templar, Thomas, Triumph, 1910-1967 (Box 17)
    - Vauxhall, Vellie, Victory Six, Waverley, Westcott, Wheeling, Whippet, White, Winton, Woods, 1903-1959 (Box 17)
    - Volkswagen, 1959-1970 (Box 17)
    - Volvo, Hayes, Renault, Fiat, Simca, Rolls Royce, 1920-1974 (Box 17)
    - Britain, 1908-1957 (Box 17)
    - Britain--Armstrong Siddeley, Austin, 1907-1953 (Box 17)
    - Britain--Hotchkiss, Jaguar, 1911-1956 (Box 17)
    - Britain--Rolls Royce/Hooper/Bentley, 1922-1957 (Box 17)
    - Britain--Rover/Land Rover, 1952-1957 (Box 17)
    - Britain--Vander Plas, Vauxhall, 1922-1957 (Box 17)
    - Britain--Willys Overland Crossley, Wolseley, 1920-1927 (Box 17)
    - France, 1909-1937 (Box 17)
    - France--Citroen, 1919-1959 (Box 17)
    - France--Delage, Delahaye, 1921-1937 (Box 17)
    - France--Mathis, Peugeot, 1931-1937 (Box 17)
    - France--Renault, 1914-1959 (Box 17)
    - Spain--Hispano Suiza, 1924-1933 (Box 17)
    - Cars and trucks miscellaneous, 1914-1969 (Box 43)
  - Parts and Accessories, 1917-1965; 2
    - General, 1917-1965 (Box 18)
    - Hughes, 1947-1948 (Box 18)
  - Petroleum Products (including agricultural chemicals), 1908-1968; 3
    - American/Amoco, 1931 (Box 2)
    - BP (British Petroleum), 1921-1956 (Box 2)
    - Esso (Standard Oil), 1956-1963 (Box 2)
    - Ethyl, 1931-1933 (Box 2)
    - Gulf, Sunoco, 1921-1935 (Box 2)
    - Newsprint, 1918-1919 (Box 2)
    - Phillips, Shell, 1924-1962 (Box 2)
    - Socony-Vacuum/Mobil, 1911-1944 (Box 2)
    - Texaco, 1922-1947 (Box 2)
    - American (Amoco), 1963-1965 (Box 18)
    - BP, 1922-1957 (Box 18)
    - Esso/Humble/Standard, 1927-1965 (Box 18)
    - Ethyl, 1929-1939 (Box 18)
    - General, 1909-1957 (Box 18)
    - Quaker State, 1929-1968 (Box 18)
    - Shell, 1910-1968 (Box 18)
    - Socony-Vacuum (Mobil), 1908-1967 (Box 18)
    - Texaco, 1922-1959 (Box 18)
    - Veedol, 1918-1938 (Box 18)
  - Tires, 1897-1968; 4
    - BF Goodrich, 1920-1963 (Box 2)
    - Dunlop, 1897-1953 (Box 2)
    - Firestone, 1908-1928 (Box 2)
    - Fisk, 1910-1925 (Box 2)
    - Goodyear, 1930-1964 (Box 2)
    - Kelly (Kelly Springfield), 1908-1923 (Box 2)
    - Michelin, 1903-1921 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous, 1905-1934 (Box 2)
    - Newsprint, 1916-1919 (Box 2)
    - Pennsylvania Rubber Co., 1906-1924 (Box 2)
    - Pirelli, 1920 (Box 2)
    - United States Rubber Co. (US Royal/Uniroyal), 1919-1963 (Box 3)
    - Dunlop, 1910-1960 (Box 19)
    - Firestone, 1909-1968 (Box 19)
    - Fisk, 1914-1952 (Box 19)
    - General, 1912-1968 (Box 19)
    - Goodrich, 1910-1970 (Box 19)
    - Goodyear, 1910-1965 (Box 19)
    - US Rubber (US Royal), 1912-1966 (Box 19)
  - Trucks (including industrial equipment), 1900-1966; 5
    - Autocar, 1947-1949 (Box 3)
    - Bethlehem, 1917-1918 (Box 3)
    - Caterpillar, 1918 (Box 3)
    - Chevrolet, 1922-1948 (Box 3)
    - Clydesdale, 1919-1920 (Box 3)
    - Denby, 1916-1919 (Box 3)
    - Diamond-T, 1918-1920 (Box 3)
    - Ford, 1951 (Box 3)
    - Four Wheel Drive Auto Co., 1919-1920 (Box 3)
    - General Motors, 1919-1920 (Box 3)
    - Grabowsky, 1908-1910 (Box 3)
    - International, 1912-1949 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous, 1900-1936 (Box 3)
    - REO, 1918-1947 (Box 3)
    - Republic, 1917-1919 (Box 3)
    - Selden, 1914-1919 (Box 3)
    - Service, 1919-1920 (Box 3)
    - Stewart, 1917-1928 (Box 3)
    - Studebaker, 1949-1950 (Box 3)
    - White, 1912-1951 (Box 3)
    - Caterpillar, 1931-1944 (Box 19)
    - Cheverolet, 1929-1963 (Box 19)
    - Ford, 1937-1966 (Box 19)
    - General, 1910-1957 (Box 19)
    - General Motors, 1936-1965 (Box 19)
    - Graham, Paige, Studebaker, 1919-1946 (Box 19)
    - International, 1926-1965 (Box 19)
    - Reo, 1929-1951 (Box 19)
    - White, Willys, 1913-1956 (Box 19)
- Business, 1883-1982; 2
  - Aetna, 1915-1949 (Box 3)
  - Alfred Dunhill, 1934-1979 (Box 3)
  - American Express, 1907-1956 (Box 3)
  - American Federation of Musicians, 1930 (Box 3)
  - Bank of America, 1946-1968 (Box 3)
  - Bank of New York, 1934-1973 (Box 3)
  - Bergdorf Goodman, 1929-1954 (Box 3)
  - Container Corporation of America, 1950 (Box 3)
  - Crouch Fitzgerald, 1913-1928 (Box 3)
  - Davey Tree Surgeons, 1920-1930 (Box 3)
  - Dunhill Tailors, 1966-1979 (Box 3)
  - Equitable, 1904-1906 (Box 3)
  - ER Squibb Sons, 1922-1934 (Box 3)
  - FAO Schwarz, 1899-1972 (Box 3)
  - Forbes Business and Finance, 1956 (Box 3)
  - Grinnell, Three-in-One, 1922-1950 (Box 3)
  - Guaranty Trust, 1913-1958 (Box 3)
  - Gyer-Cornell, 1935 (Box 43)
  - Harriman National Bank, 1913-1931 (Box 3)
  - Hartford Fire Insurance, 1911-1921 (Box 3)
  - Hornblower Weeks, 1944-1948 (Box 3)
  - IBM, 1942-1949 (Box 3)
  - John Hancock, 1948-1964 (Box 3)
  - Liberty Mutual, 1956-1958 (Box 3)
  - Lloyd's Bank, 1928-1931 (Box 3)
  - Massachusetts Mutual, 1957-1963 (Box 3)
  - Metropolitan Life, 1935-1957 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 1905-1982 (Box 3)
  - Mutual of New York, 1954-1960 (Box 3)
  - National City, 1929 (Box 3)
  - New York Life Insurance, 1905-1935 (Box 3)
  - Newsprint, 1913-1950 (Box 3)
  - Prudential, 1899-1951 (Box 3)
  - Real Estate, 1925-1950 (Box 3)
  - Saks Fifth Avenue, 1930-1951 (Box 3)
  - Swaine Adeney Ltd (UK), 1922-1925 (Box 3)
  - Union Carbide, 1929-1957 (Box 3)
  - Upjohn, 1947-1948 (Box 4)
  - Utility companies, 1914-1949 (Box 4)
  - Wells Fargo, 1914-1918 (Box 4)
  - Woodward Lothrop, 1944-1977 (Box 4)
  - Advertising and Broadcast, 1931-1946 (Box 20)
  - Aetna, 1930-1968 (Box 20)
  - Alcoa, 1928-1938 (Box 20)
  - Alfred Dunhill, 1947 (Box 20)
  - American Express, 1927-1946 (Box 20)
  - Bank of America, 1931-1968 (Box 20)
  - Bank of New York, Chase National Bank, 1945-1967 (Box 20)
  - Bell System, Western Electric, 1914-1958 (Box 20)
  - Bergdorf and Goodman, 1928-1937 (Box 20)
  - Container Corp of America, 1937-1953 (Box 20)
  - Corning, 1938-1941 (Box 20)
  - Davey Tree Surgeons, 1931-1953 (Box 20)
  - Dow Chemical, 1937-1944 (Box 20)
  - DuPont, Glidden, Pittsburgh, 1926-1942 (Box 20)
  - Eaton, Krupp, IBM, Merck, Continental Can, 1934-1951 (Box 20)
  - Equitable, 1904-1965 (Box 20)
  - ER Squibb Sons, 1934-1937 (Box 20)
  - FAO Schwartz, 1948-1959 (Box 20)
  - Grinnell, 1963-1965 (Box 20)
  - Guaranty Trust Co., 1933-1942 (Box 20)
  - Harriman, Lloyd's Bank, 1925-1953 (Box 20)
  - Hartford Fire Insurance, Insurance Co. of North America, Northwestern Mutual, 1921-1959 (Box 20)
  - John Hancock, 1942-1960 (Box 20)
  - Kimberly Clark, Kleerfect, 1930-1942 (Box 20)
  - Liberty and Co., 1883-1936 (Box 20)
  - Liberty Mutual, 1937-1958 (Box 20)
  - Metropolitan Life, 1940-1966 (Box 21)
  - Miscellaneous, 1916-1971 (Box 21)
  - Morgan Guaranty, US Fidelity and Guaranty, 1943-1971 (Box 21)
  - Mutual of New York, 1907-1967 (Box 21)
  - Massachusetts Mutual, New England Mutual, 1958-1968 (Box 21)
  - Mead, Monsanto, Otis, Postage Meter, 1934-1952 (Box 21)
  - New York Life, 1914-1959 (Box 21)
  - Prudential Insurance, 1904-1966 (Box 21)
  - Real Estate, 1916-1966 (Box 21)
  - Republic Steel, Reynolds, Timken, 1938-1956 (Box 21)
  - Russwin Erwin, Swaine Adeney, 1920-1926 (Box 21)
  - Saks Fifth Avenue, 1929-1950 (Box 21)
  - Union Carbide, 1934-1957 (Box 21)
  - Upjohn, 1942-1946 (Box 21)
  - Wells Fargo, Western Bancorporation, Westminster Bank, 1928-1969 (Box 21)
- Fashion, 1883-1986 and undated; 3
  - Apparel, 1900-1982; 6
    - Accessories, 1905-1982 (Box 4)
    - Accessories--Riding whips, canes, umbrellas, 1920-1939 (Box 4)
    - Arrow/Cluet, 1906-1923 (Box 4)
    - Austin Reed's, 1921-1953 (Box 4)
    - Burberry, 1918-1982 (Box 4)
    - Burdine's, 1934-1944 (Box 4)
    - Chanel Couture, 1939-1960 (Box 4)
    - Corsets/Foundations, 1905-1942 (Box 4)
    - Erte, 1922 (Box 4)
    - French ads, 1930-1938 (Box 4)
    - Gamages, 1917-1918 (Box 4)
    - Gieves, 1921-1939 (Box 4)
    - Hart Shaffner Marx, Kuppenheimer, 1918-1919 (Box 4)
    - Hermes, 1928-1947 (Box 4)
    - Hosiery, 1900-1921 (Box 4)
    - J.W. Robinson Co., 1936-1955 (Box 4)
    - Jantzen, 1928-1958 (Box 4)
    - Jean Patou, 1922-1957 (Box 4)
    - Knapp-Felt, Wooltex hats, 1908-1915 (Box 43)
    - Menswear, 1901-1979 (Box 4)
    - Outerwear, 1917-1931 (Box 4)
    - Outerwear--Aquascutum, 1913-1951 (Box 4)
    - Paul Stuart, 1953-1958 (Box 4)
    - Pringle of Scotland, 1947-1970 (Box 4)
    - Stetson, 1919 (Box 4)
    - Sulka, 1927-1960 (Box 4)
    - Thresher, 1918-1920 (Box 4)
    - Women's wear, 1926-1957 (Box 4)
    - Women's wear--McCall's magazine, 1918 (Box 4)
    - Accessories, 1917-1942 (Box 22)
    - Accessories--Riding Whips, Canes, Umbrellas, 1920-1928 (Box 22)
    - Bell Jardiniere, 1913-1921 (Box 22)
    - Burberry, 1919-1942 (Box 22)
    - Chanel Couture, 1933-1964 (Box 22)
    - Corsets/Foundations, 1901-1940 (Box 22)
    - French Ads, 1911-1939 (Box 22)
    - Gieves, 1920-1952 (Box 22)
    - Hermes, 1925-1934 (Box 22)
    - Hosiery, 1907-1924 (Box 22)
    - Jantzen, 1926-1959 (Box 22)
    - Jean Patou, 1925-1936 (Box 22)
    - Menswear, 1905-1958 (Box 22)
    - Menswear--Austin Reed's/Thresher, 1917-1938 (Box 22)
    - Miscellaneous, 1908-1959 (Box 22)
    - Mossant Hats (Fr.), 1925-1938 (Box 23)
    - Outerwear, 1923-1929 (Box 23)
    - Outerwear--Aquascutum, 1908-1932 (Box 23)
    - Revillon Freres (Furs), 1923-1959 (Box 23)
    - Sulka, 1921-1954 (Box 23)
    - Women's Apparel, 1915-1952 (Box 23)
  - Designers/Stores, 1915-1986 and undated; 7
    - Alfred Dunhill, 1934 (Box 4)
    - Bloomingdale's (catalogs), 1976-1984 (Box 4)
    - Brooks Brothers, 1925-1940 (Box 5)
    - Henri Bendel, 1919-1972 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 5)
    - Saks Fifth Avenue, 1926-1956 (Box 5)
    - Sears (catalog), 1941 (Box 5)
    - Woodies (Christmas catalog), undated (Box 5)
    - Alfred Dunhill, 1934-1938 (Box 23)
    - Brooks Brothers, 1915-1939 (Box 23)
    - Burdine's, 1932-1947 (Box 23)
    - Henri Bendel, 1935-1956 (Box 23)
    - Esprit De Corps catalogs, Neiman Marcus Christmas Catalogs, 1979-1986 (Box 24)
  - Fabrics, tailoring, etc., 1899-1939; 8
    - Miscellaneous, 1903-1939 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1914-1935 (Box 23)
    - The Tailor's Review, 1899-1900 (Box 5)
  - Footwear, 1900-1953; 9
    - Church's, 1910-1953 (Box 5)
    - Manfield, 1916-1928 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1900-1942 (Box 5)
    - Footwear, 1905-1941 (Box 23)
    - Footwear--Manfield, 1914-1918 (Box 23)
    - Footwear--Regal, 1904-1919 (Box 23)
  - Jewelry, 1883-1982; 10
    - Angelus, 1947 (Box 5)
    - Bailey, 1929 (Box 5)
    - Black Starr Gorham, 1927-1953 (Box 5)
    - Boucheron, 1938 (Box 5)
    - Buccellati, 1972-1974 (Box 5)
    - Bulgari, 1973-1975 (Box 5)
    - Cartier, 1934-1977 (Box 5)
    - Ciro Pearls, 1922 (Box 5)
    - DeBeers, 1944-1963 (Box 5)
    - Garrard Co., 1956-1959 (Box 5)
    - Goldsmiths and Silversmiths, 1900-1919 (Box 5)
    - Gubelin, 1946-1959 (Box 5)
    - H. Lewkowitz, 1953-1954 (Box 5)
    - Mauboussin, 1929-1949 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1924-1982 (Box 5)
    - Newsprint, 1926-1951 (Box 5)
    - Tiffany, 1905-1974 (Box 5)
    - Trifari, 1945-1953 (Box 5)
    - Van Cleef and Arpels, 1943-1975 (Box 5)
    - Ciro Pearls, 1919-1926 (Box 25)
    - Cyma, Tavannes, 1924-1964 (Box 25)
    - DeBeers, 1938-1969 (Box 25)
    - Garrard, 1925-1931 (Box 25)
    - Miscellaneous, 1883-1951 (Box 25)
    - Tecla, 1911-1929 (Box 25)
    - Tiffany, Trifari, 1911-1964 (Box 25)
    - Cartier, 1930-1976 (Box 27)
    - Harry Winston, 1950-1978 (Box 27)
    - J.E. Caldwell Co., 1928-1930 (Box 27)
    - Van Cleef Arpels, 1942-1976 (Box 27)
  - Watches, 1901-1977; 11
    - Audemars Piguet, 1949-1958 (Box 5)
    - Bulova, 1952-1963 (Box 5)
    - Comcord, 1949-1956 (Box 6)
    - Cyma, 1930-1954 (Box 6)
    - Doxa, 1949-1958 (Box 6)
    - Elgin, 1907-1959 (Box 6)
    - Eterna, 1947-1959 (Box 6)
    - Girard Perregaux, 1946-1958 (Box 6)
    - Gruen, 1930-1943 (Box 6)
    - Hamilton, 1939-1956 (Box 6)
    - Incabloc, 1951 (Box 6)
    - International, 1949-1959 (Box 6)
    - Juvenia, 1940-1954 (Box 6)
    - Longines, 1913-1959 (Box 6)
    - Mido, 1946-1953 (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous, 1901-1968 (Box 6)
    - Movado, 1944-1959 (Box 6)
    - Newsprint, 1918-1970 (Box 6)
    - Omega, 1948-1977 (Box 6)
    - Patek Philippe, 1946-1974 (Box 6)
    - Piaget, 1963-1968 (Box 6)
    - Rolex, 1944-1979 (Box 6)
    - Tissot, 1946-1953 (Box 6)
    - Universal Geneve, 1946-1974 (Box 6)
    - Watchmakers of Switzerland/Accurist/Eska, 1949-1954 (Box 6)
    - Wyler, 1947 (Box 6)
    - Zenith, 1950-1959 (Box 6)
    - Bulova, 1946-1967 (Box 25)
    - Eterna, 1937-1963 (Box 25)
    - Girard Perregaux, 1945-1957 (Box 25)
    - Gruen, 1922-1951 (Box 25)
    - Hamilton, 1935-1965 (Box 25)
    - Helbros, 1929-1967 (Box 25)
    - Incabloc, 1950-1955 (Box 25)
    - Jaeger- Le Coultre, 1930-1974 (Box 26)
    - Juvenia, Mido, 1945-1965 (Box 26)
    - Longines, 1918-1950 (Box 26)
    - Miscellaneous, 1915-1958 (Box 26)
    - Movado, 1930-1953 (Box 26)
    - Omega, 1902-1952 (Box 26)
    - Patek Philippe, 1934-1963 (Box 26)
    - Rolex, 1941-1964 (Box 26)
    - Tourneau, Tissot, 1939-1965 (Box 26)
    - Ulysse Nardin, 1929-1948 (Box 26)
    - Universal Geneve, 1937-1965 (Box 26)
    - Vacheron Constantin, Waltham, Wyler, Zodiac, 1932-1977 (Box 26)
    - Watchmakers of Switzerland, 1948-1959 (Box 26)
    - Belforte/Benrus, 1958-1967 (Box 27)
    - Gubelin, 1945-1966 (Box 27)
    - Uhren Beyer (Ad in German), 1963 (Box 27)
- Food and Beverage, 1840-1971 and undated; 4
  - Beverages, 1891-1971 and undated; 12
    - Alcoholic--Beer--Anheuser-Busch, 1908 (Box 6)
    - Alcoholic--Brandy/Cognac--Hennessey, 1901-1969 (Box 6)
    - Alcoholic--Whiskey, 1947-1964 (Box 6)
    - Alcoholic--Wine/Sherry--Moet, 1937-1968 (Box 6)
    - Non-alcoholic--Coca-Cola, 1906-1949 (Box 6)
    - Non-alcoholic--Miscellaneous, 1891-1931 (Box 6)
    - Non-alcoholic--Postum, 1902-1922 (Box 6)
    - Non-alcoholic--Sanka, 1938-1939 (Box 6)
    - Non-alcoholic--Schweppes, 1959 and undated (Box 6)
    - Non-alcoholic--Vittel, 1915-1950 (Box 6)
    - Non-alcoholic--Welch's, 1911-1920 (Box 6)
    - Non-alcoholic--White Rock, 1945 (Box 6)
    - Non-alcoholic--Yuban, 1913-1960 (Box 6)
    - Alcoholic--Beer, 1911-1953 (Box 28)
    - Alcoholic--Beer---Budweiser, 1911-1964 (Box 28)
    - Alcoholic--Beer---Guinness, 1932-1938 (Box 28)
    - Alcoholic--Brandy/Cognac---Courvoisier, 1948-1953 (Box 28)
    - Alcoholic--Brandy/Cognac---Hennessy, 1900-1962 (Box 28)
    - Alcoholic--Brandy/Cognac---Martell, 1905-1971 (Box 28)
    - Alcoholic--Gin, 1917-1959 (Box 28)
    - Alcoholic--Liqueurs, 1903-1938 (Box 28)
    - Alcoholic--Liqueurs---Byrrh, 1934-1936 (Box 28)
    - Alcoholic--Liqueurs---Cherry Heering, 1951-1957 (Box 28)
    - Alcoholic--Vodka---Smirnoff, Alcoholic--Rum, 1956-1965 (Box 28)
    - Alcoholic--Whiskey, 1892-1959 (Box 28)
    - Alcoholic--Whiskey---Black White, 1928-1956 (Box 28)
    - Alcoholic--Whiskey---Dewar's, 1924-1957 (Box 28)
    - Alcoholic--Whiskey---Haig, 1920-1947 (Box 28)
    - Alcoholic--Whiskey---Johnny Walker, 1914-1957 (Box 28)
    - Alcoholic--Whiskey---Seagram, 1934-1937 (Box 28)
    - Alcoholic--Whiskey---Schenley, 1917, 1952-1953 (Box 28)
    - Alcoholic--Whiskey---Vat G9, 1931-1960 (Box 28)
    - Alcoholic--Whiskey---White Horse, 1947-1953 (Box 28)
    - Alcoholic--Wine/Sherry, 1905-1956 (Box 28)
    - Alcoholic--Wine/Sherry---Moet/Dom Perignon, 1934-1963 (Box 28)
    - Non-Alcoholic, 1895-1953 (Box 29)
    - Non-Alcoholic--7up, 1944-1951 (Box 29)
    - Non-Alcoholic--Cafe Du Bresir, 1934-1936 (Box 29)
    - Non-Alcoholic--Canada Dry, 1935-1964 (Box 29)
    - Non-Alcoholic--Chase Sanborn, 1956-1957 (Box 29)
    - Non-Alcoholic--Coca Cola, 1924-1965 (Box 29)
    - Non-Alcoholic--Dr. Pepper, 1943-1957 (Box 29)
    - Non-Alcoholic--Evian, 1926-1936 (Box 29)
    - Non-Alcoholic--Ovaltine, 1922-1942 (Box 29)
    - Non-Alcoholic--Perrier, 1907-1961 (Box 29)
    - Non-Alcoholic--Sanka Coffee, 1911-1936 (Box 29)
    - Non-Alcoholic--Schweppes, 1928-1957 (Box 29)